Finding Aid for the Richard P. Wunder Research Files, 1945-1989 MS.02
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
- Series II: Hyacinth Rigaud, 1950-1987, 10.0 Linear feet (20 boxes)
  - Subseries 1: Artwork, circa 1950s-1970s
    - Zurich, Switzerland (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Unknown location (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Oversize Photographs and Images, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 2: Writings, 1954-1977
    Gallenkamp's writings on Rigaud include published articles with drafts, notes, photographs, and correspondence; the beginnings of a catalogue raisonn├®; and his thesis.
    - Article - "An Early Portrait Group by Hyacinthe Rigaud,"Gazette des Beaux-Arts, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
      Contains publication, photocopied extract of article, drafts and notes.
    - Article - [Cardinal de Bouillon and Louis XIV], 1977 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Contains notes, photos, research publications.
    - Article - "Metaphysics and Subterfuge: L'Abbe de la Trappe, Saint-Simon and Hyacinthe Rigaud,"Art Bulletin, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Contains correspondence, photographs, notes (possibly never published).
    - Article - "Problems and Discoveries in the Art of Hyacinthe Rigaud", undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Contains draft, notes.
    - Article - "Rigaud's Portrait Group at Ottowa,"Journal of Warburg and Courtald Institutes, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Contains publication, reprint, photocopy, galley.
    - Article - "Rigaud's Portrait Group at Ottowa,"Journal of Warburg and Courtald Institutes, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
      Contains drafts and notes.
    - Catalogue raisonné, A-B, undated (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
      Partial draft of catalog.
    - Preface to "La Famille et le Milieu Social du Peintre Rigaud" by Claude Colomer,Connaissance du Roussillon, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
      Contains copies of the publication, annotated drafts of Colomer's thesis (orginally written in 1959 for the Sorbonne), correspondence, and notes.
    - Proposed thesis - "Hyacinthe Rigaud, French Portraitist, 1659-1743", 1954 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Contains correspondence.
    - Thesis - "Hyacinthe Rigaud," Harvard, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
      2 copies (one annotated, one library copy)
  - Subseries 3: Lectures, 1961, 1962, 1977
    Contains drafts, correspondence, and notes regarding lectures Gallenkamp delivered.
    - "Cardinal and King," Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Contains draft, correspondence, notes.
    - "Cardinal and King," Middlebury College, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Contains correspondence, notes, clippings.
    - "Painting of the Bourbon Style of Versailles, Scenes and Portraits," Chicago Art Institute, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Contains draft, correspondence, notes. Photographs from the Treasure of Versailles Exhibit that this lecture was given in conjunction with can be found in the Research Materials subseries.
  - Subseries 4: Correspondence, 1964-1987
    Correspondence consists of many French language questionnaires that were sent out to gain information about Rigaud works, along with their replies; other correspondence regarding Gallenkamp's Rigaud research; and inquiries about Rigaud fielded by Wunder after Gallenkamp's death.
    - Various correspondents, A-Z, 1967-1980 (Box 33, Folder 1-3)
    - Colomer, Claude, 1961-1974 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      In part regarding Gallenkamp's preface to Colomer's publication,La famille et le Milleu Social.
    - Manhart, William H., 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Richard P. Wunder's correspondence re: various Rigaud inquiries after Gallenkamp's death, 1980-1987 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Questionnaires ("Gens de Chateaux"), 1964 (Box 34, Folder 1-6)
      French language questionnaires and responses regarding Rigaud provenance information.
    - Questionnaires ("Gens de Chateaux"), 1964 (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
  - Subseries 5: Subject Files, circa 1950-1970s
    Files consist mainly of notes, but may also contain correspondence, photographs, or printed material.
    - Aesthetics (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Analogies - Artists, Musicians, Writers etc. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Analogies - Children (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Analogies - Group Portraits (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Analogies - Heads, detail (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Analogies - History Painting (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Analogies - Men in Armor (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Analogies - Monarchs in State Dress (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Analogies - Prelates (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Analogies - Religious Subjects (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Analogies - Sculpture (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Analogies - Statesmen (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Analogies - Women, old (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Analogies - Women, young (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Analogies - Young Men, Old Men, without professional designation (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Articles on Portraits (about associated artists) (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Articles to be written (possibly books) (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Bibliography, books (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography, catalogs (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Bottin Mondain (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Catalogue Raisonné, ideas for schema (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Charts (color, centimeter to inch) (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Collin de Vermont, Hyacinthe (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Engravings (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Engravings, photographs (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Exhibitions (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Genealogical Research (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Group Portraiture (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Iconography (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Contains photographs.
    - Illustrations for Book (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Institut de France - Manuscripts (Rigaud ledger copies) (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Instructions and Procedures (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Interpretation of the Book (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - L-O (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - de Noble, Librarie (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - P (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Photographers (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, Witt Library (Box 38, Folder 10)
      Contains no photographs.
    - R (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - S - V (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Shop data on Rigaud assistants (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - de Troy, François (photographs) (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Unknown Portraits (photographs) (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 6: Research Material, circa 1960s
    Contains various notes, clippings, photographs, and other material relating to Gallenkamp's Rigaud research.
    - Chronologies, undated (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
    - Itinerary for private collections, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      Contains list of correspondents etc. Possibly related to "gens de chateaux" questionnaire.
    - Microfilm - "Catalogue des Portraits grauy d'apres auxpients per Monsieur Rigaud" and "Hyacinthe Rigaud, Portraitistes François", undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
      Small positive photograph images from the microfilm collection at the Bibliotheque Nationale.
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper articles regarding Rigaud, 1963-1965 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Notebook containing chart organized by engraver, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Note cards, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
      Portrait file - cards are arranged alphabetically by sitter and may contain the name and dates of the sitter, measurements of the portrait, collection or location, provenance, exhibition information, notes, and a small photograph glued to back.
      Biographical cards of sitters - arranged alphabetically.
      Located in Note Card Boxes 2-5.
    - Notes, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Photographs - Treasures of Versailles Exhibit, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
      Chicago Art Institute exhibit where Gallenkamp delivered a lecture. Material regarding this lecture can be found in the Lecture subseries.
    - Photographs - various Rigaud artwork, undated (Box 40, Folder 3-5)
    - Signature of Rigaud, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 7: Printed Material, 1950-1978
    Contains published works by others on the topic of Rigaud. Includes articles and monographs published between 1850 and 1947.
    - Bulletin du Musée Carnavalet v.3 no. 1-2, 1950 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Inventaires Après Décès D'Artistes et de Collectionneurs Français du XVIII Siecle by Daniel Wildenstein, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Le Livre de Raison du Peintre Hyacinthe Rigaud by J. Roman, 1919 (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
      Two copies, one annotated.
    - "Peintures et Sculptures Fran├ºaises au Ch├óteau d'Azay-le-Ferron" by M. Boris Lossky, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - A la Recherche du Vrai Portrait de Rance by L. Aubry, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Retables Baroques du Roussillon by Eugene Cortade, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Rigaud et sus Graveurs edited by Emile Paul, 1914 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - The State Portrait by Marianna Jenkins, 1947 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Assorted Catalogs, 1959-1978 (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    - Assorted articles regarding Rigaud, 1850-1975 (Box 42, Folder 3-5)
      Positive photostats and photocopies.
      Some oversize articles stored on MS Oversize Box B.
    - Assorted articles regarding Rigaud, 1850-1975 (Box 43, Folder 1-3)
  - Subseries 8: Miscellaneous (unrelated to Rigaud), 1953-1964
    Contains a small amount of material found with the Gallenkamp material that does not relate to his Rigaud research.
    - Course Outline - "Man in the Western World as Seen in Art and Literature," NYU, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Essay - "Three Eighteenth Century French Pastel Portraits", 1953 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      Written for Fine Arts course.
    - French postage stamps, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Photographs not related to Rigaud, undated (Box 43, Folder 7-8)
- Series III: Emmanuel Leutze, 1965-1975, 1.25 Linear feet (3 boxes)
  Emmanuel Gottlieb Leutze was a German-American history painter best known for his painting Washington Crossing the Delaware. This series contains materials regarding a Smithsonian exhibition of Leutze paintings and preparation of a biography and catalogue raisonn├®. Wunder was involved with these projects during his tenure as Curator of Painting and Sculpture for the National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian. Included are artwork files, correspondence, notes and clippings, and various writings on Leutze.
  - Subseries 1: Artwork Files, circa 1965-1970
    Folders are arranged by subject, works are arranged alphabetically within each folder. Files consist mainly of provenance forms, although some works may include photocopied images, correspondence regarding provenance, other research materials, and rarely photographs.
    - Historical subjects (Box 43b, Folder 1-2)
    - Inspired by literature (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Landscapes (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Portraits, A - H (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Portraits, J - L (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Portraits, L - W (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1966-1970
    Contains correspondence with Raymond Stehle, a Leutze scholar, regarding publication of a biography and catalogue raisonn├®. Also includes correspondence with a variety of correspondents regarding a possible NCFA Leutze exhibit, and publication of the biography and catalogue raisonn├®, and various other requests for photographs etc. Also contains photocopies of Leutze correspondence from the 1850s held in the Smithsonian.
    - Raymond Stehle, 1966-1970 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - General, 1966-1969 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Emanuel Leutze (with and regarding), circa 1850s (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: Research Materials, 1966-1968, undated
    Contains newspaper clippings and notes regarding Leutze.
    - Newspaper clippings, 1966-1968 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Notes, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4: Writings and Printed Material, circa 1965-1975
    Contains writings about Leutze by Raymond Stehle, a published Leutze monograph by Barbara Groseclose, and various photocopied articles and catalogs whose publication dates range from 1865-1975.
    - "Annotated List of the Works of Emanuel Leutze" by Raymond Stehle (photocopy), undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "Emmanuel Leutze, 1816-1868" by Raymond Stehle (photocopy), undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
      Photocopy
    - Emmanuel Leutze, 1816-1868: Freedom is the Only King by Barbara S. Groseclose for the National Collection of Fine Arts (Smithsonian), 1975 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "The Life and Works of Emanuel Leutze" by Raymond Stehle (photocopy), undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Various articles and catalogs, circa 1865-1975 (Box 45, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Artist Files, circa 1948-1965, 3.5 Linear feet (7 boxes)
  Contains Wunder's files for predominantly Italian artists from the 16th through 19th centuries. Contains photographs of artwork, and additionally some files may contain correspondence, printed material, biographical notes, or descriptions of works of art. Several folders do not contain any images of artwork.
  - Adam, Robert, 1728-1792 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Anesi, Paolo, 1697-1773 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Asselijn, Jan, d. 1652 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Bachiacca, 1494-1557 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Bandinelli, Baccio, 1493-1560 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Barocci, Federigo, 1528-1612 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Battaglioli, Francesco, ca. 1710-1796? (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Batoni, Pompeo, 1708-1787 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Bazzicaluva, Ercole, ca. 1610-after 1661 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Belanger, François-Joseph, 1744-1818 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Bellotto, Bernardo, 1721-1780 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Berchem, Nicolaes, 1620-1683 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Bianco, Baccio del, 1604-1656 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Bigari, Vittorio, 1692-1776 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Bison, Giuseppe Bernardino, 1762-1844 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Bisschop, Cornelis, 1630-1674 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Bloemen, Pieter van, 1657-1720 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Blondel, Jacques-François, 1705-1774 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Boissieu, Jean-Jacques de, 1736-1810 (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Bonone, Carlo, 1569-1632 (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Bosch, Hieronymus, d. 1516 (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Both, Jan, 1618?-1652 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Bouchardon, Edme, 1698-1762 (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Bourdon, Sébastien, 1616-1671 (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Breenbergh, Bartholomeus, 1599?-1657 (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Brill, Paul (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Buti, Giovanni Antonio (Box 46, Folder 27)
  - Calvaert, Denys, ca. 1540-1619 (Box 46, Folder 28)
  - Cambiaso, Luca, 1527-1585 (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Campagnola, Domenico, ca. 1500-1564 (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Canaletto, 1697-1768 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Canova, Antonio, 1757-1822 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Cantarini, Simone, 1612-1648 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Carlevaris, Luca, 1663-1730 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Carpi, Girolamo da, 1501-1556 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Carracci family (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Catafalques (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Cavedone, Giacomo, 1577-1660 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Cerquozzi, Michelangelo, 1602-1660 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Cesari, Giuseppe, 1568-1640 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Chiarottini, Francesco, 1748-1796 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Cigoli, Ludovico Cardi da, 1559-1613 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Clérisseau, Charles-Louis, 1721-1820 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Coccorante, Leonardo, 1700-1750 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Cochin, Nicolas, 1610-1686 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Codazzi, Viviano, 1604-1670 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Coecke van Aelst, Pieter, 1502-1550 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Collantes, Francesco, 1599-1656 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Conca, Sebastiano, 1680-1764 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Costa, Giovanni Francesco, 1711-1773 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Cresti, Domenico, 1559-1638 (il Passignano) (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Cuyp, Jacob Gerritsz., 1594-1652 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Dall, Nicholas Thomas, d. 1777 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Danby, Francis, 1793-1861 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Daubentan (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Delen, Dirck van, 1605-1671 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Demachy, Pierre-Antoine, 1723-1807 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Desiderio, Monsú (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Desprez, Louis-Jean, 1743-1804 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Dosio, Giovanni Antonio, 1533-ca. 1609 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Dughet, Gaspard, 1615-1675 (Box 48, Folder 14a)
  - Falcone, Aniello, 1607-1656 (Box 48, Folder 14b)
  - Falda, Giovanni Battista, ca. 1640-1678 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Farris, P. (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Fontebasso, Francesco, 1707-1769 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Fragonard, Jean-Honoré, 1732-1806 (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Franken, Frans II (1581-1642) (Box 48, Folder 19)
  - Gagliardi, Filippo, d. 1659 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  - Gandy, James, 1619-1689 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Gargiulo, Domenico, ca. 1609-1675 (Box 48, Folder 22)
  - Gaspari family (Box 48, Folder 23)
  - Genoels, Abraham, 1640-1723 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Ghezzi, Pier Leone, 1674-1755 (Box 48, Folder 25)
  - Ghisolfi, Giovanni, ca. 1623-1683 (Box 48, Folder 26)
  - Glauber, Jan, 1646-ca. 1726 (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Greco, Gennaro, 1663-1714 (Box 48, Folder 28)
  - Guardi, Francesco, 1712-1793 (Box 48, Folder 29-30)
  - Guercino, 1591-1666 (Box 48, Folder 31)
  - Heemskerk, Martin van, 1498-1574 (Box 48, Folder 32)
  - Hogarth, William, 1697-1764 (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - Homer, Winslow, 1836-1910 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - Hoogstraten, Samuel van, 1627-1678 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - Huet, Jean-Baptiste, 1745-1811 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - Joli, Antonio, ca. 1700-1777 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Jones, Inigo, 1573-1652 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Jordaens, Jacob, 1593-1678 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Kobell, Ferdinand, 1740-1799 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - La Fage, Raymond, 1656-1684 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Lajoue, Jacques de, 1686 or 7-1761 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Lallemand, Jean-Baptiste, 1716-1803? (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Lanfranco, Giovanni, 1582-1647 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Lastman, Pieter, 1583-1633 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - La Traverse, Charles Fran├ºois Pierre de, 1726-ca. 1780 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Lingelbach, Joannes, 1622-1674 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Lint, Hendrik Frans van, 1684-1763 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Locatelli, Andrea, 1695-1741 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Lorrain, Claude, 1600-1682 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Le Lorrain, Louis Joseph, 1715-1759 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Luti, Benedetto, 1666-1724 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Magnasco, Alessandro, 1667?-1749 (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Manglard, Adrien, 1695-1760 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Maratti, Carlo, 1625-1713 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Marchini, Giovanni Francesco, ca. 1672-1745 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Marieshi, Michele, 1696-1743 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Maso da San Friano, 1536-1571 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Mazo, Juan Bautista Martinez del, ca. 1613-1667 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Mazzola Bedoli, Girolamo, ca. 1500-1569 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Mazzoni, Sebastiano, 1611-1678 (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Miel, Jan, 1599-1663 or 4 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Moeyaert, Claes Cornelisz, 1592 or 3-1655 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Mola, Pier Francesco, 1612-1666 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Moretto, da Brescia, 1498?-1554. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Moroni, Giovanni Battista, ca. 1523-1578 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Moucheron, Isaac de, 1667-1744 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Muziano, Girolamo, 1532-1592 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Mytens, Daniel, 1590-1648 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Novelli, Pietro Antonio, 1729-1804 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Orlandi, Stefano, 1681-1760 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Palma, il Giovane, 1544-1628 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Pancelli, Giuseppe (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Panini, Francesco (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Panini, Guiseppe (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Paris, Pierre-Adrien, 1745?-1819 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Parmigianino, 1503-1540 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Passarotti, Bartolomeo, 1529-1592 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Patch, Thomas, 1725-1782 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Patel, Pierre, 1605-1676 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Paltronieri, Pietro, 1673-1741 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Percier, Charles, 1764-1838 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Perino, del Vaga, 1500 or 1501-1547 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Pernet, Jean Henry Alexandre, ca. 1763-1789. (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Peruzzi, Baldassarre, 1481-1536 (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Pietro, da Cortona, 1596-1669 (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Pietro, da Cortona, 1596-1669 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Pillement, Jean, 1728-1808 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Piranesi, Giovanni Battista, 1720-1778 (Box 51, Folder 3-5)
  - Poelenburg, Cornelis van, 1586-1667 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Polidoro, da Caravaggio, ca. 1495-ca. 1543 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Poussin, Nicolas, 1594?-1665 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Pozzo, Andrea, 1642-1709 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Puget, Pierre, 1620-1694 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Quarenghi, Giacomo, 1744-1817 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Restout, Jean, 1692-1768 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Ricci, Marco, 1676-1729 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Ricci, Sebastiano, 1659-1734 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Rinaldi, Raffaele (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Robert, Hubert, 1733-1808 (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
  - Roberti, Domenico, b. 1690 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Romano, Giulio, 1499-1546 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Rosa, Salvatore, 1615-1673 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Ruthart, Carl Andreas, ca. 1640-1672 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Sacchi, Andrea, 1599?-1661 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Saint-Aubin, Gabriel Jacques de, 1724-1780 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Saint Non, Jean Claude Richard de, 1727-1791 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Santi, Giovanni, ca. 1435-1494 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Salimbeni, Ventura, 1568-1613 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Sallembier, Henri, 1753-1820 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Salviati, Francesco, 1510-1563 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Scamozzi, Vincenzo, 1552-1616 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Scorel, Jan van, 1495-1562 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Seekatz, Johann Conrad, 1719-1768 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Servandoni, Jean-Nicolas, 1695-1766 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Shirlaw, Walter, 1838-1909 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Soane, John, Sir, 1753-1837 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Steenwyck, Hendrik van, ca. 1550-1603 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Swanevelt, Herman van, 1603-1655 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Taverner, William, 1703-1772. (Box 52, Folder 22)
  - Teniers, David, 1610-1690 (Box 52, Folder 23)
  - Tiepolo, Giovanni Domenico, 1726?-1804 and Tiepolo, Giovanni Battista, 1696-1770 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  - Tironi, Francesco, 1745-1797 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Tischbein, Johann Heinrich Wilhelm, 1751-1829 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Troy, Jean-François de, 1679-1752 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Valeriani, Domenico (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Vanloo, Jean-Baptiste, 1684-1745 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Van Uyttenbroeck, Moses, 1590-1648 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Velde, Willem van de, 1633-1707 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Vanni, Francesco, 1563-1610 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Wittel, Gaspar van, 1652 or 3-1736 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Vanvitelli, Luigi, 1700-1773 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Vasari, Giorgio, 1511-1574 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Verdier, François, 1651-1730 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Veronese, 1528-1588 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Visentini, Antonio, 1688-1782 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Vleughels, Nicolas, 1668-1737 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Weenix, Jan Batist, 1621-1660 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Wilson, Richard, 1713-1782 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Wtewael, Joachim, 1566-1638 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Zais, Giuseppe, 1709-1784 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Zick, Januarius, 1730-1797 (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - Zocchi, Giuseppe, 1711-1767 (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Zoffany, Johann, 1733-1810 (Box 53, Folder 22)
  - Zuccarelli, Francesco, 1702-1788 (Box 53, Folder 23)
  - Zuccari family (Box 53, Folder 24)
  - Zucchi, Antonio, 1726-1795 (Box 53, Folder 25)
- Series V: Architectural Drawings, 1958-1975, 4.0 Linear feet (8 boxes)
  Contains correspondence, photographs, published catalogs, drafts, notes, and promotional materials for five of Wunder's research projects that relate to architectural drawings (four in conjunction with an exhibition and catalog publication).
  - The Architect's Eye
    A 1962 Cooper Union exhibition of about 150 architectural drawings and prints selected from their collection. Wunder wrote the introduction to the catalog.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 3)